One of the most commonly used data sources in quant rating is the stock price and volume.
量化交易最常用的数据来源之一是股价和交易量
We will refer to this as price-volume,
称之为量价
but you may also hear it referred to as technical factors.
有时候还称为技术因子
The raw data for price-volume can include
量价原始数据
anything that we learn from a quotes and trade feed.
可以包含从报价和交易输入中发现的任何信息
For example, adjusted and unadjusted prices,
例如 调整后和未调整价格
the open, high, low,
每个时间段的开盘价
close for each time period.
最高价 最低价和收盘价
Different time frequencies such as day, week,
不同的时间频率 例如天 周 小时 分钟
hour, minute, and bid-ask price quotes.
以及出价和要价
There are operations that we can apply it to
我们可以对量价数据应用一些运算
the price volume data in which we also defined the window length,
并且定义窗口长度
which is how many days worth of data to use in the calculation.
即计算时使用多少天的数据
We've already seen returns,
我们已经知道收益率
which can be daily, weekly, monthly, or yearly.
例如每日 每周 每月或每年收益率
Returns can also be calculated at shorter time scales such as seconds, minutes, hours.
收益率还可以按照更短的间隔计算 例如每秒 每分或每小时
Returns can be calculated from the close of one day to the close of the next day.
可以根据一天的收盘价与第二天的收盘价计算收益率
Returns can also be calculated on the open price to close price for the same day.
还可以按照同一天的开盘价与收盘价计算收益率
For example, the open price in the morning
例如 同一天早上的开盘价
to the close price of the afternoon on the same day.
与傍晚的收盘价
Returns can be calculated on the close price of
可以用一天的收盘价
one day to the open price of the next day.
与第二天的开盘价计算收益率
For example, the return from the close price of
例如 用周一晚上的收盘价
Monday evening to the open price of Tuesday morning.
与周二早上的开盘价计算的收益率
The last example is referred to as overnight returns,
最后一个示例称为隔夜收益率
and we'll discuss this in detail in a later lesson.
我们将在后面的课程中详细讲解隔夜收益率
We can also apply operations on a distribution of returns.
还可以对收益率分布进行运算
For instance, we can calculate the first four moments,
例如 我们可以计算前四个时刻
which are called the mean,
称为均值
variance, skew, and kurtosis.
方差 偏态和峰态
The mean describes the center of the return distribution.
均值表示收益率分布的中心
The variance describes the spread of the distribution.
方差表示分布的分散情况
The square root of variance,
方差的平方根
which is the standard deviation,
即标准差
is a common measure of return volatility.
是常见的收益率波动性衡量方式
Skew describes the amount of asymmetry.
偏态表示不对称性
A positive skew, means there are
正偏态表示
more extreme values in the positive side of the distribution.
分布图的正向有更多极端值
Kurtosis describes how much of the distribution occurs in the left and right tails.
峰态表示有多少分布区域位于左侧和右侧尾部
Stock returns distributions tend to exhibit
与正态分布相比
larger tails compared to a normal distribution.
股票收益率分布通常尾部更长
Kurtosis is often referred to as fat tails.
峰态通常称为肥尾
There's also the minimum or maximum over a certain time window.
某个时间窗口内还有最小值和最大值
Note that we'll discuss skewness in a later lesson about alpha factors.
我们将在后面关于 alpha 因子的课程中讨论偏态
So, to summarize, pretty much any
总之 几乎任何统计学
statistical or time series calculation you can think of,
或时间序列运算
is fair game for use in a price-volume driven factor.
都可以应用到量价因子上
Using price and volume as a factor,
使用量价作为因子的好处是
has a benefit of having readily available data,
可以直接获得数据
since stocks trade on exchanges and many market data vendors sell trades,
因为股票在证交所交易 很多市场数据提供商
quotes, and bar data.
会出售交易 报价和 bar 数据
The availability and regularity of the data source is nice to have,
数据来源的可获得性和规律性很重要
since other sources for factor generation such
因为生成因子的其他来源
as fundamentals are updated less frequently,
更新频率更低 例如基本面
and still other data sources such as news, social media,
并且我们所分析的股票可能没有其他数据来源
or analyst reports may not always be available for the stock that we're analyzing.
例如新闻 社交媒体或分析师报告
It's very helpful to have a factor that can generate
有一个因子能够针对股票池中的每支股票
a signal for every stock in the stock universe.
生成信号这一点很有用
This is especially helpful in quant investing,
对于量化投资来说尤其有用
since quant investing usually involves portfolios of hundreds or thousands of stocks.
因为量化投资通常涉及数百或数千支股票
Keep in mind that the higher frequency of price volume data often leads to more trading,
注意 量价数据的更新频率越高
and therefore higher portfolio turnover.
交易就越多 从而提高投资组合周转率
Since trading decisions are based on the data,
因为交易决策以数据为依据
the more often the data updates and changes,
所以数据更新的频率越高
the more often the portfolio is likely to require rebalancing.
投资组合就越有可能需要再平衡
This can be good or bad and requires careful study.
这种情况有好处也有坏处 需要认真研究
Faster signals means more information.
更快的信号会带来更多信息
More information, all other things being equal, is good.
在其他方面保持不变的情况下 更多信息是好事
However, more rebalancing means more trades and more transaction costs.
但是 再平衡次数越多 交易越多 并且交易成本越高
So, strategy that is based on
所以如果策略基于经常更新的数据
frequently updated data generally has more transaction costs.
那么通常交易成本更高
As a researcher, a key thing you need to
作为研究人员 你需要确定的关键一点是
determine is if the higher information content of the signal,
信号的信息量越大
more than offsets, the likely higher transaction costs.
是否会抵消更高的交易成本